So next we have CodePipeline.
So how do we know that
CodeCommit and CodeBuild are connected?
Well, we can connect them using CodePipeline.
So CodePipeline is going to be a way
for us to orchestrate the different steps
to have the code automatically pushed to production?
What does that mean?
Well, maybe we want to define a pipeline that takes the code
builds it, tests it, provision some servers
and then deploys the application on those servers
but it could be more complicated.
And so to orchestrate all these steps
you need a pipeline tool
and this is going to be CodePipeline.
And so you may or may not
have heard of the term CICG, which may stand
for Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery.
It is the whole concept
that every time a developer pushes the code
into a repository, it is being built, tested
and deployed on to some servers.
So if we look at CodePipeline, say we have code
as an orchestration layer,
it will take its code from CodeCommit
build it with CodeBuild, then decide to deploy it
with CodeDeploy, and may be deployed
into an Elastic Beanstalk environment as one example.
But it's just one way of building a pipeline,
okay, there's so many different ways.
So why would you use CodePipeline?
Well, the benefits is that it's fully managed.
It's compatible with so many services such
as CodeCommit, CodeBuild
CodeDeploy, Elastic Beanstalk, CloudFormation, GitHub
and other third party services and custom plugins.
And it gives you fast delivery and rapid updates.
So it is at the core of the CICD services within AWS.
And so anytime you see orchestration of pipeline
in your exam, you have to think AWS CodePipeline.
So that's it, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.